TOHO CO., LTD.
SEVEN SAMURAI
Produced by
SOJIRO MOTOKI
Screenplay
AKIRA KUROSAWA
SHINOBU HASHIMOTO, HIDEO OGUNI
Cinematography
ASAKAZU NAKAI
Music
FUMIO HAYASAKA
Starring
TOSHIRO MIFUNE
TAKASHI SHIMURA
KEIKO TSUSHIMA
YUKIKO SHIMAZAKI
KAMATARI FUJIWARA
DAISUKE KATO
ISAO KIMURA, MINORU CHIAKI
SEIJI MIYAGUCHI
BOKUZEN HIDARI
YOSHIO INABA, YOSHIO TSUCHIYA
Directed by
AKIRA KUROSAWA
Subtitles by Prospero
prospero.13t@gmail.com
During the Civil Wars,
an endless cycle of conflict left
the countryside overrun by bandits.
Peaceable folk lived in terror of the
thunder of approaching hooves...
Take this village too?
Take it! Take it!
Not so fast!
We just took their rice last fall.
They'll have nothing now.
Very well.
We'll return when
that barley is ripe.
Is there no god to protect us?
Land tax, forced labor,
war, drought...
and now bandits!
The gods want us farmers dead.
That's right.
We are better off dead.
What's all this?
Crying won't change anything.
The magistrate can do
more than collect taxes.
We can ask him for help.
We know all about him.
He shows up after they are gone,
acting big while he surveys the damage.
That's right. He is useless.
We might as well hand over
our rice and barley to the bandits
and just hang ourselves!
That'll bring the magistrate
here in a hurry.
We'll kill those bandits.
We'll kill them all.
Never again!
Let's kill them all!
Not me!
I couldn't possibly.
That's crazy talk.
So we can kill defeated
samurai, but not bandits?
Stop it! This is no time
to fight amongst ourselves.
We don't have a chance against bandits.
And when we lose?
They'll slaughter us all,
down to the last unborn child.
I've had enough!
Better to risk it all
than to live like this.
Kill or be killed!
Rikichi!
The farmer's only
choice is to endure.
We can't defy the powerful.
When the bandits arrive,
we'll greet them meekly
and quietly hand over
all our barley.
We'll plead with them to leave
just enough for us to survive.
"That's all we ask,"
we'll beg on our hands and knees.
What bandit will agree to that?
Have you forgotten how low we had
to stoop for the rice we're eating now?
We should go see the Old Man.
Let him decide what to do.
Consider who we are dealing with here.
Give a wolf a taste of your leg
and he'll ask for your hand.
Once they have a taste,
they'll be back in the fall.
But what if we lose?
Then we're no worse off!
Without our barley,
we are doomed anyway!
We fight.
Old Man, that's madness.
We are farmers.
What do we know of battle?
We'll hire samurai.
Whoever heard of farmers
hiring samurai?
I saw it with my own eyes,
when the village you were
born in was torched.
I saw it when we escaped
to this village here.
The only village that didn't burn
was the one that hired samurai.
But Old Man, there are different
kinds of villages and villagers.
How are we to feed samurai
when we live on rice gruel?
We'll make do on millet.
Show me a samurai who'll fight
for farmers in return for food.
They are a proud lot.
Look.
Find hungry samurai.
Even bears come down from
mountains when they're hungry.
How dare you?
You are nothing but a farmer.
I'm still a samurai!
I don't need your charity.
Fool!
What'd I tell you?
Look, the barley is ripe.
Ten days already
since we left the village.
What do we do?
This barley is early,
not like our mountain barley.
Hey, we are soaked
through to the bone.
Find any cheap, strong
and foolhardy samurai?
Leftovers.
You can have them cheap.
That's a laugh!
What's so funny?
He is blind.
What about you, then?
Not me.
I'd rather eat horseshit.
Won't get a nose bleed outta him.
Cleaned him out gambling last night.
Pulled his sword when he lost,
so the three of us beat him up.
Not a drop left in his nose now.
Don't bother.
They only eat millet.
Is that true?
You can't live like that.
Without nourishment
you'll go night-blind.
I've got just four left.
I'll trade them all
for a cup of rice.
What do you say?
Damn! What a bunch.
What a waste.
If we still had that rice,
we coulda bought 40 of those.
Shut up!
But it is true, right?
The blockhead is cracking up!
What a show.
Go at it, boys.
Who ever heard of
anything so unfair?
We give him his fill of rice
and a free bottle of sake,
and he thanks us with a beating.
Good for him!
Not like this one
playing possum here.
Say, let's go home.
Let's just go home.
Look at him sobbing.
Misses his wifey.
I'd pay good money to watch
the two of them going at it.
Let's hurry and get
back to the village.
Go on home. You can't afford
buns, let alone samurai.
Farmers like us know good from
bad when it comes to seed,
but not when it comes to samurai.
Besides, we are no match
for the tough ones,
and the only ones
interested are weaklings.
If I lost last night, it was
only because I was starving.
Liar! You had plenty
of money to gamble.
Jerk!
Wanna fight?
It is a fight.
Over here!
Wake up!
Quit that strumming, monk!
It is depressing!
Keep it up, grandpa.
We are on your side.
Rikichi!
Stop it, Manzo!
You said we were going home,
you son of a bitch!
I said we'd go home,
not bargain with bandits.
If we can't hire samurai,
what is left?
It is bargain or nothing!
Fine, have it your way!
But tell me:
If we do strike a bargain,
what have we got
to offer this year?
Are you willing to give
them your daughter?
Shino is a fine-looking girl.
What's going on?
There is a thief in that barn.
We raised a ruckus and he ran in to hide.
How many thieves are there?
Just one.
One?
All of you can't take
a single thief?
We don't dare make a move.
He took a kid in there with him.
Says he'll kill him if we attack.
Listen. Hear him?
Poor thing.
It all happened in the
middle of the night.
Poor kid's been bawling
the better part of a day.
He can barely make a sound now.
He is only seven.
Imagine how his parents feel.
Who is that samurai
getting his head shaved?
No idea. We asked him for help
and he agreed right away.
Then he asked us
for two rice balls.
He asked a monk to shave his
head and lend him his robes.
No idea what he is up to.
Stay back!
Any closer and I kill the brat.
I'm a monk.
Stay back!
I'm just a monk.
I mean you no harm.
I won't come in.
I just thought the child
must be very hungry.
I've brought some rice balls.
You should eat one yourself.
Won't you have one?
What's wrong?
Throw them here!
Here.
My baby!
Even you can't object
to a samurai like that.
Ask him quickly.
It'll be harder in town.
What do you want?
My name is Katsushiro Okamoto.
Please make me your disciple!
Disciple?
As you see, I'm a ronin.
The name is Kambei Shimada.
I don't take on disciples.
Get up.
I can't talk to you like this.
I'm begging you.
Let me be your disciple.
First get off your knees.
We'll talk as we go.
I'm at a loss.
You think far too highly of me.
No, sir.
Just hear me out.
There is nothing special about me.
I may have seen
my share of battle,
but always on the losing side.
That about sums me up.
Better not to follow
such an unlucky man.
No, I'm determined to follow you
whether you allow me to or not.
I forbid it.
I don't have the means
to travel with an attendant.
Can I help you?
What do you want?
Insolence!
Stay out of this, little chick.
Are you a samurai?
Damn right I am!
I wonder.
Bastard.
Who was that?
Leave him be.
I beg of you, sir!
You idiot.
Why don't you scram?
Stubborn old fool.
They'll eat it and run like last time.
It will never work.
Sir, we could arm the villagers
with bamboo spears.
I thought of that.
But, sir.
This isn't a game.
They may be bandits,
but they ride 40 strong.
Two or three samurai won't suffice.
Defense is more difficult
than offense.
You say there are mountains
behind the village?
Yes.
Passable by horse?
Fields in front.
Until those are flooded with water,
you're open to mounted
attack on four sides.
You need at least four men,
one to guard each side.
Two more to guard the rear.
No matter how frugal
our estimate,
we need seven, including me.
We can manage seven somehow.
But the Old Man said four.
It is only three more.
Hold on a second.
I haven't accepted your offer.
I'm only speculating.
First of all, it is not easy
to find trustworthy samurai.
What's more, all you
have to offer is food.
Only those out to fight
for the hell of it will agree.
Besides, I'm sick of fighting.
Age, I suppose.
Good thing I wasn't born a peasant.
Better to be born a dog.
Goddamn it.
Go ahead, hang yourself and die!
You are better off dead!
Silence, you lout!
What's it to you?
I'm only telling the truth.
What truth? What the hell do you
know of these farmers' suffering?
Don't make me laugh!
Like you would know.
How dare you?
You heard right. If you know,
why don't you help them?
So you wanna fight?
That's enough.
Enough!
Hey, samurai, look at this.
This here is your dinner.
But what do you think
these blockheads eat?
Millet.
They eat millet to
feed you white rice.
This is the best they can offer.
What do you say to that?
All right, then.
What?
Quit your jabbering.
I won't let this rice go to waste.
Manzo and the others are back.
Where are Rikichi and Yohei?
They stayed behind.
We still need more samurai.
The samurai are coming?
They sure are.
Seven of them.
Seven?
Seven.
I was against it because
you said four, Old Man.
I figured we'd need
at least ten.
But if I'd said ten,
we'd have ended up with 15.
That's the way it goes.
Old Man, I'm worried.
The village girls will go
crazy over the samurai.
If the samurai touch them,
all hell will break loose.
Bandits are coming, you fool.
Your head is on the block,
and all you think of
is your whiskers?
Samurai, sir.
You require my services?
Yes, sir.
Who is to be my opponent?
Katsushiro.
Hide just inside the door.
Strike that ronin as he enters.
Here he comes.
Don't hold back.
Give him a real whack.
Excellent!
Please don't take offense.
I am Kambei Shimada.
We're seeking expert swordsmen
and have no time to waste.
Forgive me.
What's this about?
The reason better be good,
or I'll have to redeem my honor.
I humbly beg your pardon.
We only sought to test your skill.
We must soon contend
with a gang of bandits.
I see.
And whose clan do you serve?
It pains me to tell you,
but we are fighting for farmers.
Farmers?
That's right.
This job affords no
stipend and no reward.
But we can eat our fill
as long as we fight.
This is absurd!
My ambitions are greater than that.
That's a shame.
Won't you reconsider?
I will not.
Sir, we lost a good man there.
Such a fine swordsman.
What's wrong?
That one samurai is good,
but how'll the other six be?
Enough of your worrying.
How can we know before they get here?
Don't worry till you've seen them.
That one there.
Excuse me, samurai, sir.
Just like last time?
Sure. It is good practice for you.
Surely you jest.
No offense intended.
I'm with you.
But I have to say that
although I understand
the farmers' suffering
and understand why you
would take up their cause,
it is your character that
I find most compelling.
In life one finds friends
in the strangest places.
What is your name?
Gorobei Katayama.
A name fit for a giant, no?
Yohei, what are you doing?
Hurry and wash the rice.
Yohei!
What is wrong?
Someone stole the rice.
You idiot!
Didn't I warn you?
I was so careful.
I slept the whole night
hugging that rice jar.
Fine, then!
I'll get more from home.
But what'll we do
till you get back?
There is only a handful left.
Stop that, you idiot!
Hide that money.
The master is returning.
I ran into you at
just the right time.
So you are still alive. I figured
you'd long since left this earth.
Now tell me,
what happened after that?
I hid among the grasses
in the moat until dark.
When the outer walls tumbled down
on me in flames, I knew I was finished.
What ran through your
mind at that moment?
Nothing special.
Sick of fighting yet?
Truth is, there is a tough battle ahead
leading to neither money nor rank.
Will you join us?
Yes.
This may be the
one that kills us.
Where are they
when you need them?
What do you need, sir?
Samurai.
There is a pretty poor excuse
for one in my backyard.
I couldn't believe his gumption.
He says,
"I'm hungry. Feed me.
I'm broke though, so I'll
pay you by chopping wood."
I like his frankness.
Never seen a man
split wood before?
Sure, but you do it
with such relish.
It is just my nature.
Sorry if it bothers you.
You are very good.
It is nothing compared
to how I cut down men.
Have you cut down many?
Yes, I have.
There is no cutting me off
when I start cutting.
So I make it a point
to run away first.
A most excellent approach.
Why, thank you kindly.
Tell me, do you feel like
cutting down 30 bandits?
Let us commence!
Too bad.
It is a draw.
No.
I won.
That's ridiculous!
If these were steel,
you'd be dead now.
Then we fight with steel!
Don't throw your life away.
What?
Don't you see?
With steel blades, you'd die.
It is a waste of your life.
Wait! Don't try to flee.
Draw! This isn't
a contest of words.
This is preposterous.
There is no contest.
How did you fare?
We let a good fish get away.
An excellent swordsman.
They say the fish that gets away
looks bigger than it really is.
No.
I watched him cut a man
down with my own eyes.
It was amazing.
A man obsessed only with
testing the limits of his skill.
I doubt he'll join us.
That's a shame.
Indeed.
I did tell him where we
are staying, though.
And how did you fare?
Caught one.
I see.
As a swordsman, barely mediocre.
Barely mediocre?
But an honest, amusing man.
Something about him
brightens one's spirits.
He'll be a treasure in hard times.
Much obliged.
Actually, I did land one myself.
The one dressed as a peddler?
That's right.
In fact, he is an old trusted friend.
I'll bring some water.
I'm Heihachi Hayashida.
A modest warrior of
the Wood-Chop School.
Just three more to go.
Three? Don't you mean two?
No, we can't afford
to take a child along.
Master!
I know, I know.
I know what you'll say.
I was once your age, you know.
Hone your skills,
then go to war
and do great things.
Then become lord of your
own castle and domain.
But as you dream those dreams,
before you know it,
your hair will turn
as gray as mine.
By that time
you've lost your parents
and you're all alone.
Tomorrow you go home.
You've learned a lot
these four or five days.
You have fine stories to tell.
Please, sir.
I beg you to let him come along.
Why not let him come?
You call him a kid, but...
Actually,
kids work harder than adults.
But only if you treat
them like adults.
Then let's treat him like an adult.
That means only two more.
Actually just one, it seems.
You wish to join us?
I'm very grateful.
When do we depart?
Tomorrow.
Tomorrow?
This is enough. We don't have
time to find the last one.
All right, then.
Master!
All right.
All right! That's enough of that!
Hey, I just found
a real tough samurai.
There was a huge fight.
They were no match for him.
Never seen anything like it.
He is like a wild dog.
Someone stopped the fight.
They started drinking.
I told him about you.
He is on his way.
Shall we give him the usual?
What are you doing?
Testing him.
That's a dirty trick!
Hey, samurai!
Just shut up and watch.
A true samurai won't get hit.
But this guy is drunk!
A samurai never drinks
enough to dull his wits.
I told you!
You guys are nuts.
What the...
Who the hell hit me?
You?
Who hit me?
Damn bastard!
You again!
I see that bald head of
yours in my dreams!
Hey, you.
How dare you even ask
me if I'm a samurai!
You got some nerve!
Don't mess with me.
I may look like hell,
but I'm a real samurai.
I've been looking for you
ever since that day.
Wanted you to see this.
Look at this!
This is my family tree.
All my ancestors are here.
Damn you, trying to make
a fool outta me. Screw you.
Look here.
Making a fool outta me.
My honorable self is right here.
So this Kikuchiyo here
would be you?
That is correct.
"Kikuchiyo,
born February 17, 1574."
What's so damned funny?
You hardly look
13 years old to me.
If you are in fact
the Kikuchiyo listed here,
you'd now be precisely
13 years old.
Where did you steal
this family tree?
Steal it? Shit!
Damn jerks.
To hell with samurai.
To hell with samurai!
Hey, you bastard!
Come back here!
Goddamn it,
you son of a bitch!
What's wrong, teenager?
Here you are.
Damn you!
Come back here!
What's wrong, Lord Kikuchiyo?
What's the matter, junior?
Screw samurai!
Is he really a samurai?
In his own mind, anyway.
Take me too!
Hey, Kikuchiyo.
Guard your treasure.
Let me go too!
What is it, Father?
What is it?
What are you staring at?
Shino, cut off your hair.
Cut your hair and
dress like a man.
What are you talking about?
Just cut it off!
It is only because I love you.
No telling what those samurai'll do!
No!
No, I won't!
Shino!
He is a fool.
But Manzo knows those samurai
better than anyone.
If he cuts off his daughter's hair,
he must have a good reason.
You've only got sons,
so you're safe, but we...
Goddamn it!
Now I understand.
So you agree to hide my daughter
at your place across the bridge?
Idiot! I meant that I see
what Manzo is up to.
That rascal doesn't care about
the village, only about his daughter.
Damn him!
Look what you've done!
Now the whole village is crazed.
Every family with a girl is gone mad.
How do you plan
to set this right?
The samurai will
show up any day now.
Come on.
We are seeing the Old Man.
There is nothing to see here.
Go home!
We can't let the samurai
see us like this.
He is still following us.
Where did Kikuchiyo go?
Think he gave up?
It is funny.
Now that he is gone,
it is almost a little...
Ionely.
This way.
Oh, hell!
So that's our castle?
No way I'm gonna die
in that dungheap.
No one asked you to.
We are back!
The samurai have arrived.
The samurai are here!
What's wrong with you?
Hey, what's wrong?
What is the matter?
This is a fine welcome.
What is the meaning of this?
Hey, what is going on?
The samurai have arrived.
We'll go see the Old Man.
The Old Man?
Whatever happens in the village,
the Old Man...
He is the village elder?
An audience with the village elder.
This is truly an honor.
Well, let's go.
I know they are being foolish.
All farmers ever do is worry,
whether the rain falls, the sun
shines, or the wind blows.
In short,
all they know is fear.
Their behavior today...
is also due simply to fear.
But Old Man,
why do the villagers fear us?
What can they expect from us
under such circumstances?
Samurai, sirs!
Samurai, please!
Quiet down!
Don't panic! Calm down.
I want clear answers.
Where are the bandits coming from?
The mountains!
No, the road!
Who saw the bandits?
Come forward.
No one saw any bandits?
Then who sounded the alarm?
I did!
Outta the way.
What's with the faces?
Don't worry.
No bandits have come.
Hey, blockheads.
Remember how you welcomed
us when we got here?
But as soon as I bang on this,
"Samurai, sirs!
Samurai, please!"
You're practically groveling!
Got what you deserved,
you mud snails.
Got a problem, gramps?
Nope.
All is well now.
Looks like he is good
for something after all.
There are seven of us at last.
Sorry it is so dirty.
But where will you sleep
if we take your home?
In the barn.
With your horse?
The bandits got my horse last year.
A barn is not so bad with
a wife to snuggle up to.
I don't have a wife!
What's the matter?
Jerk.
By the way, what is your real name?
I don't remember.
Give me a new one that fits.
Then Kikuchiyo it is.
Fits you perfectly.
How would you attack this village?
I'd charge from this mountain.
I agree.
Along this road.
WEST
And what is the best defense?
Shichiroji knows what to do.
See these logs? He'll make
a fence to block the horses.
Indeed. Your trusty right-hand man.
All right!
Listen.
Nothing forces you
to run like a battle.
You run when you attack,
you run when you retreat.
When you can't run
anymore, you die.
SOUTH
We'll flood these fields
after they harvest the barley.
That'll make a good defense.
But will we have time?
Indeed.
Charge!
Pretend I'm a bandit
and stab me.
Charge!
Come on!
Next.
What's wrong with all of you?
EAST
Destroying this bridge will
foil an assault from the east.
But what about the houses
on the other side?
They'll have to evacuate those.
And the mill?
The Old Man isn't
going to go quietly.
Listen now.
The enemy is scary.
Everybody is scared.
But the other side is
scared of us too.
Just great.
You all make great scarecrows.
Problem is, the enemy isn't a
bunch of sparrows and crows.
You there, chewing your cud.
Can you cut that out?
This isn't a cow shed.
Look at the bunch of you.
Shit!
First in line, step forward!
I'm talking to you.
You!
Look here! You gotta pay a
mon each to watch the show.
What's this?
A spear, sir.
Idiot.
Where the hell
did you get it?
Did it sprout up in those hills?
I know perfectly well.
You hunted down retreating
warriors and took their weapons.
If you've got one,
you must have more.
Fess up, damn it!
NORTH
What a peaceful grove.
But it is also a death trap.
Katsushiro.
We're going.
I'll be right there.
As I said, he is still a child.
Are you from the village?
Are you a girl?
A boy?
Then where is your spear?
Is this any time for an able-bodied
man to be picking flowers?
Come here!
I'll teach you.
Why, you!
This is fine, and this too.
But this is a problem.
Heave ho! Heave ho!
Get back, the rest of you!
Stand up straight!
What a haul!
What's all this?
Plunder from defeated warriors.
Where did you find it?
Here in the village?
Yep, over at Manzo's.
What's the matter?
Don't you like them?
This is good stuff.
What's wrong?
You said you wanted armor,
spears and bows. Now you got them.
Bastard!
You call yourself a samurai?
Those farmers killed
samurai to get these.
I know that.
Then why the hell...
That's enough!
You can't understand
unless you've been hunted.
It is nothing.
Get outta here.
Now I want to kill them all.
Well, that's just fine and dandy.
What did you think these
farmers were anyway?
Buddhas or something?
Don't make me laugh!
There is no creature on
earth as wily as a farmer.
Ask them for rice, barley, anything,
and all they ever say is,
"We're all out."
But they've got it.
They've got everything.
Dig under the floorboards.
If it is not there, try the barn.
You'll find plenty.
Jars of rice, salt, beans, sake!
Go up in the mountains.
They have hidden fields.
They kowtow and lie,
playing innocent the whole time.
You name it,
they'll cheat you on it!
After a battle, they hunt down
the losers with their spears.
Listen to me!
Farmers are misers, weasels,
and crybabies!
They are mean, stupid
murderers!
Damn!
I could laugh till I cry.
But tell me this:
Who turned them into such monsters?
You did.
You samurai did.
Damn you to hell!
In war, you burn their villages,
trample their fields,
steal their food,
work them like slaves,
rape their women,
and kill them if they resist.
What do you expect them to do?
What the hell are farmers
supposed to do?
Damn it! Goddamn it!
You were born a farmer,
weren't you?
What is it now?
Nothing at all.
Everything is fine.
It is me.
I'm sleeping here from now on.
Those guys cramp my style.
Idiot! Stop cowering!
This is your place.
You hand over your house
and sleep in a barn,
and still you can't
stand up for yourself.
Get to sleep!
Brings back memories.
Sure is quiet.
On a day like this, it is hard to
imagine bandits on that mountain.
Damn it all,
I need a girl.
Where are you going?
The hills.
The hills?
To practice.
No girls up there.
Sometimes you really
hit the nail on the head.
What are you making there?
A flag.
A flag?
It doesn't feel right in battle
without a banner to raise high.
What do the symbols mean?
This represents a field:
that is the farmers and this village.
And those circles?
Those are us.
There is only six.
You leaving me out?
No, this triangle is Lord Kikuchiyo.
That's a good one!
It is real rice.
Go ahead. Eat.
But...
Rikichi gave me some millet.
I could barely get it down.
Go ahead. Eat.
Hurry up and eat.
If you're embarrassed, I'll go.
I'm not going to eat it.
Why not?
I went to a lot of trouble.
No, I just...
I know you did, so I'll take
it to Kyuemon's grandma.
Kyuemon's grandma?
Rikichi, I'm full.
I'll save the rest for later.
Go ahead and eat.
Take my leftovers this time.
What's this?
What are you up to?
What's going on?
How terrible.
Doesn't she have family?
The bandits got them all.
I...
want to die quickly.
I want to die soon
and leave this suffering behind.
But you know...
the other world may be
just as full of suffering
as this one.
It is not.
In that world there is
no war and no bandits.
There is no suffering there, grandma.
How the hell would you know?
Have you been there?
Why the hell are you always screaming?
I hate wimps.
Worms like her make me sick!
Pissing and grumbling
about everything.
Shit!
I want to do something wild.
Save your spit and
fire for the bandits.
Excuse me.
Excuse me, but why did you...
You saw us today, didn't you?
Me and the...
The girl?
Yes.
Why didn't you...
Tell them? You want me to?
We want rice!
White rice!
You little brats!
There is no rice.
Quit yapping!
If you've got the strength
to scream, "We want rice!"
Then you don't need it.
Listen here, you little piss pants.
This is all the rice there is.
If we give you any more,
we'll get all...
That's how it is.
Say, any of you got
a pretty sister?
How about you?
You got one?
So, Old Man,
when is the harvest?
In ten days.
How quickly can you do it?
No less than three days.
We'll flood the fields
when you are done.
You see, we want to dig a
moat to the south of the village.
It'll keep the horses out.
We don't need all the fields.
One patch per family will do.
Then...
it'll take at least a day to flatten
the paths and draw the water.
Understood.
There is one other thing.
You need to leave the houses this
side of the bridge, and the mill too.
Father!
You want us to move out?
I know it is tough.
But there is no choice.
We can't possibly protect
the outlying houses.
Listen carefully. You'll soon
begin harvesting the barley.
The bandits will come
when you're done.
We have to assume that.
Therefore we prepare
for battle as we harvest.
We'll harvest not as
families but as squads.
Starting tomorrow, each squad
will live and work as one.
Understood? Starting tomorrow,
nobody acts on his own.
Hey, everybody.
Give your wives plenty of
loving tonight, you hear?
This is all a load of crap.
Everyone from across
the bridge, follow me.
Throw down your spears.
Why should we abandon
our homes to protect theirs?
That's right.
We'll protect our homes ourselves.
Stop!
Pick up your spears!
Return to your line!
Fall in!
Squad formation!
Where is Yohei gone?
Where the hell is Yohei?
There you are, you idiot!
There are three outlying houses,
but 20 in the village.
We can't risk 20 to save three.
And if this village is destroyed,
those three cannot
survive on their own.
Is that clear?
This is the nature of war:
By protecting others,
you save yourself.
If you only think of yourself,
you'll only destroy yourself.
From this day forward,
anyone caught doing that...
INTERMISSION